# **ALEXIS QUINTUÑA**

alexisiquintuna@gmail.com I (646) 730-3569

# linkedin.com/in/alexis-quintuna | github.com/alexisquintuna | alexisquintuna.com

Passionate full-stack web developer, with a knack for using new technology and tools to elevate clients' brands. Using my academic experience to build dynamic applications, in all aspects of the user experience and user interface.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Object-Oriented Programming: .Net | JavaScript

Web Application Development: HTML | CSS | ASP.NET Core | Vue.js | React | Node.js | Express | TailWind

Database Programming: ADO.NET | Table Design | E/R diagrams | MVC | MongoDB

Development Tool & Techniques: Agile | Unit Testing | REST | Figma | Postman | SquareSpace | Wordpress | WIX

#### TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

**TrainingGrounds -** Redesigned a daycare website, increasing the target audience by 15% and reducing site production by nearly 2 weeks. Worked closely with the client to gather requirements and ensure that the new design met their needs. Developed a user-friendly and visually appealing website that was easy to navigate and use. Successfully launched the new website on time and within budget.

CatCrack - Developed a landing page with WordPress and Javascript, allowing users to view what CatCrack has to offer. This includes a product overview, a contact form, and a page displaying the company's social media posts. Provided user satisfaction while delivering an exceptional user experience through motion design. The landing page features a scrolling animation introducing the product and its benefits. The user experience made the site gain an audience increase of over 300%. Worked with the client to ensure that the landing page met their marketing goals, designed to generate leads and drive sales.

OPEN CITY - Collaborated with a team to design and develop a full-stack web application that allows users to plan adventures anywhere. Implemented agile methodologies to create the user login, search for landmarks in a city, and add them to the adventure card. The adventure card contains a travel route that includes all the landmarks inside. Built with the help of VS2019 - SSMS | .Net - ADO.NET - Vue.js to create both functional and user-friendly.

**Genere Natus 2.0 -** Created and designed a landing page web app for a car club using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and React. I initially started with vanilla HTML and CSS, but then designed a new version of the site in Figma to then develop it using React to test my front-end abilities and the tools I self-taught myself. With the skills applied, I was able to generate 20% more user engagement on the site. I worked independently to manage all aspects of the project, from ideation to launch.

# **EDUCATION**

# Tech Elevator, Columbus, OH

**SEPT 2022 – DEC 2022** 

Attended a 14-week full-stack coding boot camp learning how to create dynamic web-based software systems using .NET/C# providing 800+ hours of development education and application.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### The Roosevelt Coffeehouse, Columbus, OH

SEPT 2019 - PRESENT

Lead Barista

- Operated a coffee shop with a proven track record of success, generating over \$3000 in daily sales and consistently receiving positive feedback.
- Demonstrated ability to juggle multiple projects and roles effectively, adapting to the company's needs and being a team player
- Took ownership of new different requests, identified growth opportunities, and increased sales by 15%

# Astra Studio, Columbus, OH

January 2023 - PRESENT

Contract Web Developer

- Enhanced the team by quickly learning the company's workflow and procedures, sharing new perspectives and ideas, and helping the team to find innovation solutions
- Secured, executed, and completed two projects on time and within budget, receiving positive feedback from clients and co-workers, working closely with clients to gather requirements and deliver a product that met their needs

- Demonstrated the ability to handle multiple projects simultaneously and think quickly on my feet, successfully resolving unexpected challenges, adapting to changing circumstances, and prioritizing tasks
- Devoted to learning new tools and technologies, such as WordPress, Squarespace, and Wix, to grow the company's clientele, increasing the company's clientele by 3x, an estimated value of over \$50,000 annually

#### OfRoot, Columbus, OH

## March 2021 - August 2021

#### Web Development Intern

- Gained experience in all aspects of web development, from writing and designing web page content to developing and maintaining websites, using authoring and scripting languages to create interactive and dynamic websites
- Demonstrated strong problem-solving and analytical skills by developing detailed test plans that ensured that websites were tested thoroughly.
- Worked independently and as part of a team to deliver projects on time, collaborating with team members to share ideas and solve problems.